Hello, everyone, and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
Katrina And my name is Katrin.
我是Katrin。
And today we're talking about one of my least favorite things, Marco.
今天我们要聊一件我最不喜欢的事情，Marco。
Marco Mosquitoes.
蚊子。
They're all over the place, especially in summer or near water.
它们到处都是，尤其是在夏天或者靠近水的地方。
And for me, the worst part is when you are trying to sleep and there's a mosquito that
对我来说，最糟糕的是当你正要睡觉时，有只蚊子
just keeps on biting you and won't let you sleep.
不停地咬你，让你睡不着。
Katrina You can kind of hear it around your head, you
你几乎能听到它在脑袋周围嗡嗡响，
know, by your ears.
就在耳朵旁边。
Marco Yeah, around your ear, uh-huh.
是啊，就在耳朵旁边，嗯哼。
Katrina Oh, I hate that.
哦，我讨厌那样。
Or when you just get bitten and you're in bed and it just itches so much you can't sleep.
或者当你刚被咬了一口，躺在床上，痒得根本睡不着。
Marco Itches, and it burns sometimes.
又痒又疼，有时候还发烫。
Katrina Yeah, so that's what we're talking about
是啊，这就是我们今天要聊的，
today, fun stuff.
有趣的话题。
Let's jump right into this dialogue, and we'll be back in a minute to talk about what's going
我们直接进入对话，一会儿再回来讨论
on.
具体内容。
The mosquitoes are biting me!
蚊子正在咬我！
Me too!
我也是！
I can't stop scratching!
我忍不住一直挠！
They are everywhere, sneaky little jerks!
它们到处都是，这些狡猾的小混蛋！
I'm going to get you!
我要抓住你！
Katrina No, I forgot to buy some.
不，我忘了买一些。
Marco Then we'll have to put up with it.
那我们只能忍着了。
Katrina We can cover ourselves with beer.
我们可以用啤酒把自己涂满。
That way, if they bite us, they'll get drunk and fall asleep.
这样，如果它们咬我们，就会喝醉然后睡着。
Marco That's, without doubt, the best idea you've
这毫无疑问是你
ever had.
有过的最棒的主意。
Let's do it.
就这么办。
Katrina Run!
快跑！
They're thirsty for more!
它们还想喝更多！
All right, we're back, so let's take a look at some of these words in Language Takeaway.
好了，我们回来了，现在来看看“语言要点”中的一些单词。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, so as we mentioned, we're going to be talking about mosquitoes and well, these
好的，正如我们提到的，我们要聊蚊子，嗯，
are just little small insects that suck your blood.
它们就是那种吸你血的小昆虫。
They do and they're very thin and not much to say about them.
是的，它们很瘦小，没什么好说的。
They were very important in the movie Jurassic Park if you remember that.
如果你还记得的话，它们在电影《侏罗纪公园》里非常重要。
Right.
对。
Now, what's the difference between a mosquito and a fly?
那么，蚊子和苍蝇有什么区别呢？
Okay, a fly usually is just annoying.
嗯，苍蝇通常只是烦人。
It doesn't suck your blood, but a mosquito does.
它不吸血，但蚊子会。
It sucks your blood and flies are fatter and like shorter.
它吸你的血，而苍蝇更胖、更短一些。
And they're big and black and they're black.
它们又大又黑，是黑色的。
And they're green kind of sometimes.
有时候还有点绿。
Black and green and they, yeah, they just buzz around.
黑色和绿色，它们，嗯，就是到处嗡嗡飞。
So mosquitoes actually bite you.
所以蚊子实际上会咬你。
Okay, so a mosquito and a fly.
好的，所以蚊子和苍蝇。
Now, if a mosquito bites you, you really, really want to scratch.
现在，如果蚊子咬了你，你会非常非常想挠。
That's right.
没错。
So you feel like you need to scratch your body because you have this bite.
你会觉得需要挠身体，因为被咬了。
You know, it's really an allergy and you have a red bump on your arm, a red mark and you
你知道，这其实是一种过敏反应，胳膊上会起个红疙瘩，一个红印，你
scratch and it gets worse and worse.
一挠，情况就越来越糟。
All right.
好的。
And moving on to our next word, mosquitoes have a reputation of being sneaky.
接下来看下一个词，蚊子以狡猾著称。
Okay, so you can say sneaky about a lot of things.
嗯，你可以用“狡猾”来形容很多事情。
And, you know, obviously we're saying mosquitoes are very sneaky.
而且，你知道，我们显然是在说蚊子非常狡猾。
That means that they can kind of hide and get you when you're not expecting it.
意思是它们能躲起来，在你没防备的时候偷袭你。
Yeah, because sometimes during the day, you don't really see them in your room, right?
是啊，因为有时候白天你在房间里不太能看到它们，对吧？
They're hiding or they're in a place where you can't really see them.
它们躲着，或者藏在你看不见的地方。
And then at night, all of a sudden, they come out.
然后到了晚上，它们突然就出来了。
They come out.
它们出来了。
So, and they're very hard to see.
而且它们很难被发现。
They fly around in a way that's very difficult to catch them or kill them, right?
它们飞的方式很难抓住或打死，对吧？
Right.
对。
We could say thieves are very sneaky.
我们可以说小偷很狡猾。
Like a thief is someone who steals something and they like to sneak around and hide in
就像小偷是偷东西的人，他们喜欢偷偷摸摸地躲在
the dark.
暗处。
And then when you're not expecting it, they come out and they steal your stuff.
然后在你没防备的时候，他们出来偷你的东西。
Exactly.
没错。
And now what do we do or what do we use in order to prevent mosquitoes from biting us?
那么，我们用什么来防止蚊子咬我们呢？
This is essential, especially if you're going to the beach.
这很关键，尤其是如果你要去海滩。
We bring bug spray.
我们会带驱虫喷雾。
Bug spray.
驱虫喷雾。
So a spray is something that you can usually have in a can that you push a button and it
喷雾通常装在罐子里，你按一下按钮，
comes out.
它就会喷出来。
All right.
好的。
Right.
对。
And it's not water, but it keeps the bugs away.
它不是水，但能驱赶虫子。
So bug spray keeps bugs away.
所以驱虫喷雾能赶走虫子。
Not only mosquitoes, but like flies or any other type of bug.
不只是蚊子，还有苍蝇或其他类型的虫子。
Now specifically for mosquitoes, you would use maybe a mosquito repellent.
专门针对蚊子，你可能会用驱蚊剂。
Right.
对。
So repellent is, it means something that pushes or keeps away things you don't want.
驱蚊剂的意思就是能驱赶或远离你不想要的东西。
So something that keeps mosquitoes away is called a mosquito repellent.
所以能驱赶蚊子的东西就叫驱蚊剂。
And usually it's a cream you put on your arms or legs.
通常是一种涂在胳膊或腿上的霜。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So interesting words that we've just taken a look at.
我们刚刚看了一些有趣的词。
Let's listen to our dialogue again and we'll be right back.
让我们再听一遍对话，马上回来。
The mosquitoes are biting me.
蚊子正在咬我。
Me too.
我也是。
I can't stop scratching.
我忍不住一直挠。
They are everywhere, sneaky little jerks.
它们到处都是，这些狡猾的小混蛋。
Do you have any bug spray?
你有驱虫喷雾吗？
No, I forgot to buy some.
不，我忘了买一些。
Then we'll have to put up with it.
那我们只能忍着了。
We can cover ourselves with beer.
我们可以用啤酒把自己涂满。
That way if they bite us, they'll get drunk and fall asleep.
这样，如果它们咬我们，它们就会喝醉然后睡着。
That's without doubt the best idea you've ever had.
这毫无疑问是你有过的最棒的主意。
Let's do it.
就这么办。
Run.
快跑。
They're thirsty for more.
它们还想喝更多。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at a couple of different phrases on Fluency Builder.
现在让我们看看“流利度提升”中的几个不同短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度提升。
All right.
好的。
So the first phrase is very, very common.
第一个短语非常非常常见。
The person in the dialogue says that they're going to have to put up with it, put up with
对话中的人说他们得“put up with it”，忍受它。
these mosquitoes because they didn't have any bug spray.
这些蚊子，因为他们没有驱虫喷雾。
So this phrase, to put up with, is really important.
所以这个短语“put up with”非常重要。
All right.
好的。
So if you put up with something, it means that you tolerate it.
所以如果你“put up with”某事，意思是你容忍它。
All right.
好的。
That means even if you don't want to, you'll still handle it.
这意味着即使你不想，你也会处理它。
You'll still have to deal with it.
你仍然得应付它。
You accept it.
你接受它。
So maybe you have a little brother that's very annoying and you just have to put up
所以也许你有个很烦人的弟弟，你只能忍受
with him.
他。
There's no other option.
没有别的选择。
Yeah.
是的。
Or someone says to you, you're just going to have to put up with it.
或者有人对你说，你只能忍忍了。
Or you say, I won't put up with it anymore.
或者你说，我再也受不了了。
I won't handle this anymore.
我再也受不了了。
I'm done.
我受够了。
All right.
好的。
So I think this is a great phrase for us to take a look at a couple of different examples.
所以我觉得这个短语很好，我们来看几个不同的例子。
Example one.
例子一。
I can't put up with the noise any longer.
我再也受不了这噪音了。
Turn that music down.
把音乐关小点。
Example two.
例子二。
If you can put up with the smell, then stinky tofu is actually very tasty.
如果你能忍受那味道，臭豆腐其实很好吃。
Example three.
例子三。
I've had to put up with him for too long.
我已经忍他太久了。
I want a new roommate.
我想要个新室友。
And after this, we've got another phrase.
之后，我们还有另一个短语。
We're talking about beer.
我们在谈论啤酒。
Okay.
好的。
And so the person says, oh, I have an idea.
然后那个人说，哦，我有个主意。
Instead of bug spray, we can cover ourselves with beer.
与其用驱虫喷雾，我们可以用啤酒把自己盖住。
So to cover yourself or cover ourselves.
所以“cover yourself”或“cover ourselves”。
So it means that we put it all over us.
意思是把它涂满全身。
Right.
对。
So you could even cover yourself with bug spray.
所以你甚至可以用驱虫喷雾把自己盖住。
Okay.
好的。
So every part of your body, you put bug spray on.
所以身体的每个部位，你都涂上驱虫喷雾。
Head to toe.
从头到脚。
Now, you can cover yourself under a tree maybe.
现在，你也可以躲在树下。
Or you can cover yourself with a blanket.
或者用毯子把自己盖住。
Okay.
好的。
So to cover yourself, to completely hide under something.
所以“cover yourself”，就是完全藏在某物下面。
And finally, we have the response to this idea, the answer.
最后，我们有了对这个主意的回应，答案。
The person says, oh, without a doubt, that means absolutely or definitely.
那个人说，哦，毫无疑问，意思是绝对或肯定。
Okay.
好的。
So there is no doubt.
所以没有疑问。
It is true or it is certain.
它是真的或确定的。
Right.
对。
So a doubt is something that maybe you're not so sure about.
所以“doubt”是你可能不太确定的事情。
You're not convinced.
你没有被说服。
But you can say, this is without a doubt the best mosquito spray.
但你可以说，这毫无疑问是最好的驱蚊喷雾。
Or this is without a doubt the best cake I've ever eaten.
或者这毫无疑问是我吃过的最好的蛋糕。
That means it's definitely the best cake I've ever eaten.
意思是我吃过的最好的蛋糕。
All right.
好的。
So I think we've covered all the phrases now.
所以我觉得我们已经涵盖了所有短语。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue for the last time and we'll be right back.
我们最后听一遍对话，然后马上回来。
The mosquitoes are biting me.
蚊子一直在咬我。
Me too.
我也是。
I can't stop scratching.
我忍不住一直挠。
They are everywhere, sneaky little jerks.
它们到处都是，鬼鬼祟祟的小混蛋。
Do you have any bug spray?
你有驱虫喷雾吗？
No, I forgot to buy some.
没有，我忘了买一些。
Then we'll have to put up with it.
那我们只能忍着了。
We can cover ourselves with beer.
我们可以用啤酒把自己盖住。
That way if they bite us, they'll get drunk and fall asleep.
这样如果它们咬我们，它们会喝醉然后睡着。
That's without doubt the best idea you've ever had.
这毫无疑问是你有过的最好的主意。
Let's do it.
我们干吧。
Run.
跑。
They're thirsty for more.
它们还想喝更多。
Mosquitoes are very annoying, but at times they can be very dangerous, right?
蚊子很烦人，但有时它们可能很危险，对吧？
They can.
是的。
There are a couple of diseases that can be passed by mosquito bites.
有几种疾病可以通过蚊子叮咬传播。
One of them is malaria.
其中一种是疟疾。
And that's I think pretty common in Southeast Asia and South Asia.
我觉得这在东南亚和南亚很常见。
Now there was another situation where people believed that if a mosquito bit a person infected
还有一种情况，人们认为如果蚊子叮了感染
with HIV or AIDS, they could pass it on to another person.
艾滋病毒或艾滋病的人，它们可以传染给另一个人。
Aha.
啊哈。
Well, I don't know that that's even possible because there's no AIDS carrying mosquitoes.
嗯，我不知道那是否可能，因为没有携带艾滋病的蚊子。
But there is another disease called dengue fever.
但还有一种病叫登革热。
And this is another very dangerous one.
这也是非常危险的一种。
It's also known as break bone fever.
它也被称为“断骨热”。
And I think it's so painful, it feels like your bones are breaking.
我觉得它非常疼，感觉像骨头在断裂。
And that's where the name comes from.
这就是名字的由来。
It's very common in South America as well because we have such a tropical climate that
在南美洲也很常见，因为我们有如此热带的气候，
in the rainforests of Brazil, Peru, Colombia, it's common to see this.
在巴西、秘鲁、哥伦比亚的雨林中，经常能看到这个。
But not so much anymore.
但现在不那么多了。
Now they're eradicating it.
现在他们正在根除它。
Wow.
哇。
Alright.
好的。
So an interesting topic.
所以一个有趣的话题。
Mosquitoes are not only irritating, but can be dangerous.
蚊子不仅烦人，还可能危险。
So if you have any other questions or doubts, please come to our website englishpod.com
所以如果你有其他问题或疑问，请来我们的网站englishpod.com
and we're there to answer any questions.
我们会在那里回答任何问题。
So we'll see you on the website.
那我们网站上见。
And until next time everyone, bye bye.
下次再见，大家，拜拜。
Bye.
拜。